morpace.com 2019-05-05

# Privacy

Morpace Inc., established in 1975, is a global full-service market research and consulting organization. We provide information to our clients to help them understand the needs, purchase behaviors, and preferences of their customers.

Morpace is committed to industry quality and maintains compliance to ISO 20252, the International Standard for Market, Opinion and Survey Research. As part of this commitment, we maintain the privacy and security of personal information. We do not conduct sales or direct marketing, nor do we provide personal information to be used for direct contact sales or marketing purposes. Please view our company information on our website or contact us at [information@morpace.com](mailto:information@morpace.com) with concerns or questions.

Morpace complies with the provisions of the General Data Processing Regulation (GDPR) of 2018 along with the EU – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. Morpace has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Privacy Principles of notice, choice, accountability for onward transfer, security, data integrity and purpose limitation, access, recourse, enforcement and liability. In any case of onward transfer to third parties, Morpace is potentially liable unless it can be proved that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Privacy Principles, the Privacy Shield Privacy Principles shall govern. The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has jurisdiction over Morpace's compliance with the Privacy Shield. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, and to view Morpace’s certification, please visit www.privacyshield.gov.

Morpace is a member of the Council of Insights Association, the professional trade association of survey research companies and holds individual membership to the European Society of Opinion and Marketing Research (ESOMAR). Morpace adheres to the mandated Insights Association Code of Standards and Ethics for Survey Research. This code includes requirements for the protection of personal information and respondent identifying information. For more information, please visit the Insights Association website at <http://www.insightsassociation.org/>

Additionally, Morpace adheres to the Standards for Privacy of Individually Identifiable Health Information (Privacy Rule) as required by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA).

The Quality Manager and/or Data Protection Officer at Morpace are available to answer questions about the Morpace Privacy Policy, to request personal information corrections or amendments and for addressing complaints or disputes. We will respond to all complaints within 45 days and will strive to resolve all complaints about privacy and the collection or use of customer information. If you have any questions, information updates, complaints or would like to request a copy of the Morpace Security Policy, please email [information@morpace.com](mailto:information@morpace.com) or call 248.737.5300 and ask to speak to the Quality Manager. Morpace is committed to cooperating and complying with the EU data protection authorities for dispute resolution as well as complying with all GDPR regulations. Under certain conditions, customers have the right to invoke binding arbitration. If you feel that we have not satisfactorily addressed your complaint you can visit the EU data protection authorities at www.ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/individuals.

**Morpace Website**

The only personal information actively collected on the Morpace website is that which is voluntarily provided. Like many other websites, we use cookies to provide a better experience for our members. We limit their use for quality control and validation. Cookies are used temporarily during the time you are actively completing a survey or filling out the registration forms and we do not store or retain your cookie information in any way. No Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is transmitted via these cookies.

Personal information is safeguarded on secured systems and is used only for the purpose stated. In order to respond to an inquiry, an email address or other contact information may be requested when we are contacted through [[information@morpace.com](mailto:information@morpace.com).](mailto:information@morpace.com.) This information is shared with Morpace employees on a need to know basis only.

Our website may contain hyperlinks to websites outside of Morpace. Data collection privacy policies may be different on hyperlinked sites not owned by Morpace Inc.; therefore we recommend that the Privacy Policy / Statement is read for each site visited.

**Research Survey Information**

Personal information provided to Morpace is confidential. When entering our survey instrument you provide consent to collect and use your information. Information collected on behalf of our clients is combined with information gathered from other survey participants and shown in aggregate and may include personally identifiable information. If we indicate that personal information may be included in the research findings, we ensure that the information is treated with the strictest of confidence. We will not mislead a participant regarding the nature of the research or how the information will be used. Please see the section titled “Sharing of Personal Information by Morpace" and "Protection of Morpace Data" for more information.

Research participation is voluntary. When entering our survey instrument you are consenting to the use of your data. Participants may opt-out of current research by disregarding or declining the invitation to participate and are given the opportunity to be removed from future research conducted by Morpace. At a research participant’s request, we will correct, amend or delete incorrect personal information we have collected about them. Such access may be limited by Morpace if providing such access would violate another person’s rights.

**How we Collect Information About You**

The personal information we hold about you will vary depending on the context of your interactions with us, but typically in two forms:

  * Information collected from you in the course of research surveys completed for Morpace
  * Customer information provided by clients to Morpace for research purposes

**Information We Hold About You**   

Morpace may have personal email addresses* in its email system and/or data files that are acquired through:

  * Requests for information submitted to our website
  * Emails sent to Morpace
  * Clients who have provided email addresses for research purposes

*The CAN SPAM Act of 2003 applies specifically to commercial emails sent for the purpose of sales or direct marketing. Morpace does not fall into this category; however, it voluntarily observes the CAN SPAM Act requirements that can be applied to survey research. Morpace uses email as a means of communicating to known clients and customers. When email is used to invite respondents to participate in surveys, the following processes are used to ensure we do not send spam:

  * We clearly identify ourselves and/or the client when sending an invitation
  * We provide contact information should there be any questions or concerns
  * We provide the option to be removed from future email research invitations
  * We reuse email addresses only as a legitimate follow up to survey research

These processes ensure that we contact only those who could have an expectation of being contacted for research purposes.

Personal information we collect from your voluntary participation in our research surveys or information supplied by our clients may include, but is not limited to . . .

  * Name
  * Contact data such as email address, home and/or work postal address, phone number
  * Image and/or voice captured through photography, filming, videotaping and/or audio recording
  * Ethnographic data such as your date of birth, gender, educational background, job title, country
  * Information from your requests and /or complaints registered with us
  * Any other information which may be collected in the course of our interactions with you

**Use and Processing of Your Information**

The GDPR requires us to rely on one or more lawful bases to use your personal information. The bases below are relevant to how Morpace uses your information:

  * Where you have provided consent for us to use personal information in a certain way when you enter our survey instrument.
  * Where our clients have a legitimate interest in providing their customers’ information to us for research purposes (as long as that processing is fair, balanced and does not unduly impact participants’ rights).
  * In order to comply with a legal obligation to which we are subject.

**Sharing and Protection of Personal Information**

Personal information may be disclosed when the survey instrument clearly states that the information will be disclosed or, when a participant makes a request during the survey that can only be fulfilled by disclosing information from the survey.

Only authorized Morpace employees, vendors, contractors or partners carrying out authorized business functions are allowed to access Morpace data or databases. Morpace employees are required to sign a Confidentiality Agreement in which they agree to keep all project and respondent personal information confidential. Employees who violate the Confidentiality Agreement are subject to disciplinary actions, including termination when appropriate.

Morpace discloses personal data only to third parties who reasonably need to know such data only for the scope of the market research and not for any other purposes. Vendors, contractors, or partners who have access to survey information in connection with providing services for Morpace are required, at a minimum, to sign a Confidentiality Agreement. The Confidentiality Agreement requires them to keep the information confidential; they are not permitted to use this information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for Morpace. Third parties are required to comply with the regulations of GDPR and the Privacy Shield Principles and such recipients must agree to abide by these principles.  

If Morpace is required or permitted by law, national security or court orders to collect, use, and / or disclose personal information; notice may not be required.

In the event of a sale, merger, liquidation, dissolution, reorganization or acquisition of Morpace or a Morpace business or business unit, the acquiring party would agree to be bound by the terms of the Morpace Privacy Policy before any information would be transferred.

Morpace is committed to keeping personal data secure and will take all reasonable precautions to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration. This data is stored on our internal network servers that are protected by firewalls and other appropriate security mechanisms.

Morpace adheres to the safeguards required by the Security and Privacy Standards as established under the GDPR, EU-US Privacy Shield, Insights Association Market Research Standards, HIPAA as it relates to Electronic Protected Health Information (EPHI), as well as to all Protected Health Information (PHI).

**Children's Privacy**

Morpace does not knowingly make direct contact with children under the age of 16 to participate in research activities. If we require survey information from children, we contact the parent or guardian to arrange the survey activities and we encourage the parent or guardian to closely monitor and participate in the survey activities.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

Morpace reserves the right to modify and update this policy and its related business practices at any time. Please view this Privacy Policy on a regular basis.

If you have any questions concerning our Privacy Policy, please contact us at 248.737.5300 or [information@morpace.com](mailto:information@morpace.com).

Morpace Inc.  
Version #11  
Date: 3/11/19  
Time: 6:00 pm
